SAMUEL BLEHM

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

· +49 151 708 766 04

samuelblehm.de

github.com/src-dbgr

Highly motivated software engineer interested in Data Science with 4+ years professional experience, seeking a position to apply achieved skills, help to improve and innovate upon products and efficiency while extending domain specific knowledge. Implemented metering solutions for SAP SE which enabled monitoring capabilities, product commercialization and subsequent product adaptability within a by two digits % increased annual growth.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Oct 2016 - Dec 2020

Software Developer @ SAP SE // Walldorf, GER

- Worked with an international scrum organized team on establishing and extending Event Mesh formerly Enterprise Messaging
- Written modern, performant and robust code mainly for SAP's Cloud Platform Messaging Service
- Developed and onboarded horizontally and vertically scalable REST based applications utilizing message broker technologies
- Deployed and maintained applications on certain Cloud Platform Solutions in multiple geo locations
- Performed regular software update releases, complied with security standards by providing patches and fixing vulnerabilities
- Worked with a variety of different technologies and languages such as Java, Go, Spring Boot, Kubernetes, Message Broker
- Was responsible for a coordinated implementation project with an international partner organization aiming towards a reliable cross-broker message artifact move hosting serious customer data
- Took responsibility for emergency events such as outages with joint debugging efforts and reestablishment of critical applications which handle significant customer data
- Implemented customer instance data metering in Java which laid the foundation for pricing and monitoring measures and subsequent product commercialization
- Implemented a statistics data exporter application in Go on K8s by eliciting broker health information and instance data. Fed Prometheus Exporter and visualized in Grafana. Incident alert was pushed to Slack Messenger which led to a significant improvement of reaction time and thus reduced customer down time experience

Oct 2016 - Dec 2020

Student Assistant @ University of Mannheim // Mannheim, GER

- SAP NetWeaver Gateway rights and roles management in context of a graduate students' team project
- Assistance in lecture preparation and refactoring for "Foundations of Information Systems"
- Scientific literature analysis, evaluation upon interdependence between independent, dependent and control variables

EDUCATION

Aug 2011 - Dec 2015

University of Mannheim // Mannheim, DE

- Bachelor of Science in Business Informatics
- Deepening: Artificial Intelligence, Banking and IT Management

Jan 2014 - May 2014

Lappeenranta University of Technology // Lappeenranta, FIN

• International Business and Technology Program

HARD SKILLS

Programming Languages		Libraries & Frameworks		Tools & Platforms		Data & Design		
	Java / Go	Professionally used	Kubernetes	Professionally used	Docker	Professionally used	Adobe CC	Advanced
	SQL	Professionally used	Spring Boot	Professionally used	Maven /Jenkins	Professionally used	MS Excel	Advanced
	HTML / CSS	Advanced	Mockito	Professionally used	Grafana	Professionally used	Matlab	Basics
	JavaScript / Python	Basics	React	Basics	Git	Professionally used	Pytorch / Tensorflow	Basics

SOFT SKILLS

Soft Skills

Responsibility, self-discipline, resilience, strategic thinking, positive mindset

INTERESTS

Interests

Music, Art, Blockchain, Deep Learning / Artificial Intelligence advances